Adriana Bonilla-Ramirez

Adrianalbr12@gmail.com

Greater Atlanta Area

http://www.linkedin.com/pub/adrianabonillaramirez/

Business Analyst - Management Consultant

Energetic, creative and results-oriented leader with a strong track record of analyzing facts to resolve issues across departments and functions to create optimal operations that increase efficiency and productivity. Delivers the highest standards of quality and customer service with a positive attitude. Strong analytical mind and an unparalleled ability to adapt in an ever-changing environment with initiative and decisiveness. International experience in Europe, South America and the USA.

Selected Career Highlights:

- MBA in Management of Technology from Georgia Institute of Technology.
- Leads a team of Business/Data Analysts who support Energy Efficiency and Demand Response programs across North America
- Led the development of Konica Minolta's Client Relationship Management system to support the end to end sales cycle. A critical initiative implemented throughout 12 European subsidiaries.
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills with colleagues from all levels, diverse cultures, languages and backgrounds.
- Lean Six Sigma Green and Black Belt certified

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Franklin Energy Services – Alpharetta, GA

Oct 2015 - Present

Cell: (678) 823-5783

IT Manager

- Responsible for leading and developing a group of 9 Business/Data Analysts / Product Specialists, and 3 Project Managers that are geographically dispersed throughout the US.
- Understand the business context, strategies, and drivers for supporting GoodCents/Franklin Energy' Demand Response and Energy Efficiency solutions and emerging technology systems.
- Responsible for overseeing the process of assembling, analyzing, and translating business requirements into detailed technical requirements.
- Responsible for configuring technology tools and providing solutions to run energy efficiency and demand response programs efficiently
- Perform feasibility analysis, develop project scope, and provide recommendations on the alternative solutions, project strategy and deliverable prioritization, as well as system alternatives or enhancements to current systems.
- Research, analyze, designing, propose, and deliver solutions that are appropriate for the business and technology / product strategies.
- Improve the overall management of each of GoodCents/Franklin Energy's client accounts, creating a more cohesive process for release management and expectation setting.
- Drive innovative ideas, increasing the efficiency of our client's services, creating a seamless, uniform way of working that will simplify and reduce the number of customizations, thus reducing the number of versions of our client's core product offering.
- Foster an environment of collaboration by bringing ideas, approaches and challenges together, and resolving them as a team of subject matter experts.

Business Systems Analyst

- Responsible for assembling, analyzing, and translating business requirements into detailed requirements and functional specifications.
- Interviewed business and technical leaders to accurately document GoodCents' Demand Response processes
- Developed product standardization gap analysis and road map to institute common practices across all project offices
- Took lead role in numerous projects and consistently exceeded customer expectations
- Responsible for Sprint Planning, backlog grooming, and retrospectives with development teams
- Project managed a large migrations initiative for 12 GoodCents clients successfully meeting deadlines and client's expectations

BUZZCHIX, LLC – Atlanta GA

2014 - Oct 2017

2

Founder - CEO

BuzzChix is a technology and consulting firm. We provide management consulting, business and operations analysis services utilizing six sigma methodologies. BuzzChix's first technology solution, PPE Med, offers affordable medical supplies and medications tailored to the patient's specific condition, as well as education, support and expert advice.

- Develop consulting and business analysis opportunities
- Responsible for the strategy, sustainability and culture of BuzzChix
- Committed to deliver a complete service with competitive prices that allows patients to understand and take care of their medical conditions, and post procedure needs.
- Oversee and support the CTO, Sales & Marketing, Customer Service and Administration
- Fund Raising and strategic partnerships
- Financial analysis and reporting

CSR LLC – CONSULTING SOLUTIONS & RESULTS – Atlanta GA

2013 - 2014

Management Consultant

- Analyzed customer's business operations across several industries (telecommunications, media
 production, law firms, staffing agencies, vehicle restoration boutique, interior decoration, heating
 and air conditioning. etc.), to identify areas where existing strategy, practices, processes, software
 applications and in-house tools could be optimized to improve profitability and growth.
- Resolved staffing and operations business issues using six sigma methodologies, which resulted in over 120K savings
- Led the definition of mission, vision, values and company strategy.
- Performed in depth sales and operations cost analysis for various clients that resulted on 40% increase in profit margin.
- Gathered business requirements, and led and manage the software development life cycle
- Developed customized systems to optimized processes that resulted in sizable time saving of 70%
- Recommended, implemented, provided training, and analyzed Client Relationship Management systems (Salesforce), which resulted in higher sales conversion rates.
- Accompanied the business owner during the implementation of business changes and new initiatives efficiently avoiding major disruption in current operations

Adriana Bonilla-Ramirez 3

KONICA MINOLTA BUSINESS SOLUTIONS (UK) Ltd - United Kingdom

2007 - 2013

Business Analyst – CRM Dynamics (2010 – 2013)

• Liaise with the international IT team and the 3rd party business partner in Germany, as well users across European countries to develop the CRM system. This included generation of concept and design document, development and customization, implementation, data migration and integration testing, pilot testing, user acceptance, bug fixing, maintenance, training and reporting.

- Lead workshops involving seven departments throughout the UK (Sales, Leasing, Credit Control, Logistics, Administration, Order Processing and Bids & Tenders) and six European countries to gather business requirements, understand and identify challenges and propose solutions for the CRM development.
- Communicate effectively with programmers and users to ensure clarity and achievement of solutions, as well as to meet deadlines.
- Coordinate with the board of directors the introduction of new technology, such as CRM Dynamics, SharePoint and Tableau, amongst others in line with the company strategy.
- Provided onsite technical support for the CRM rollout program across the United Kingdom, visiting over eight cities and supporting over 300 users from January to April 2012.

Management Information Manager (2008 – 2010)

- Led and managed projects to analyze administrative processes, identify weaknesses, recommend and implement changes to streamline core business practices, increasing operational efficiency.
- Delivered quality improvements by redesigning and implementing a new commission calculation structure for the company, which decreased processing time by 80%
- Developed and implemented a new sales order process, which included an improved procedure and documentation package. This has decreased overall sales order processing time by 70%.
- Worked closely with sales directors and managers to develop programs and reports to allow the company to track key sales activities such as forecast, actual sales against budget, commission payments customer retention, and sales performance.

Sales Data Analyst (2007 – 2008)

- Instrumental in defining reporting structure and processes after migration from Oracle to SAP.
- Developed queries and reports using SAP and Business Intelligence, guaranteeing data integrity through close liaison with the IT team in Germany and various teams in the UK.
- Consulted and built relationships with customers in order to gather requirements, understand and meet their reporting needs, and meet deadlines.
- Assessed risk posed by potential new or existing customers through the production of comprehensive market, sales, spend and debt analysis reports.

INTERNATIONAL FINANCIAL DATA SERVICES (IFDS) – United Kingdom

2004 - 2007

MIS Analyst – Team Leader (2004 – 2007)

- Led a team of six data analysts, who provided daily, weekly, monthly and ad-hoc financial MIS
 reports for internal and external customers, and ensured that Key Performance Indicators reports
 were produced in an accurate and timely manner in line with existing SLA's,
- Collected, quality checked data and produced monthly root-cause analysis reports for Complaints, Breaches and MIS activity.

Breach Administrator (2005 – 2007)

Adriana Bonilla-Ramirez

 Met and consistently exceed client expectations by responding to breaches within the agreed SLA (1 day for notification and 2 days for investigation and resolution) and decrease the percentage of breaches per transactions by 40%.

EDUCATION

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Atlanta GA Executive MBA, Management of Technology

DEVRY UNIVERSITY, Alpharetta GA

BS in Business Administration - Information Systems

Certifications

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Atlanta GA Six Sigma Green Belt

PERFORMANCE EXCELLENCE, Atlanta GA Six Sigma Black Belt

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Atlanta GA Full Stack Development Certification